NO BOY NO CRY ore zenshin GO
no boy, no cry, I advance go!
shounen yo kiite kure
hey boys, listen up
ningen nante taishita mon ja nai sa
humans aren't such a big deal
ashita nante moui ranai kara
who needs tomorrow anyway
nigitta kobushi wo kakusu na yo
so don't hide your fists
fuan ni yume wo
you're not old enough
uri tobasu hodo mada oiborechainai daro
to sell your dreams away to uncertainty
shounen yo kokoro no jyuu no
hey boys, you're the only ones
hikigane wo hikeru no wa kimi dake sa
who can pull the trigger in your heart
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids said
doushi yo mo naku kudaranai
we're living in this senseless, ridiculous,
kono subarashii sekai ni tattaima ikiteiru kara
awesome world right at this moment,
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids said
subete no hontou to uso wo
don't forget every truth or lie
kesshite wasurete shima wa nai you ni
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids said
shinu ni wa mosugiru darou
we're way too young to die
shiraketa tsura ga naranderu karappo no kono machi de
in this empty town lined with empty faces
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids took off
kaze no nai kono yoru ni
into this windless night
nanika wo kaeyou to shiteru kara
because they want to change something
{Trick, Disguise, Tricked!
{The Grand Bug Mega Battle
What the heck is happening...?
Why does Hinata have
to be kidnapped?!
Why are there guys who know
that we're searching for Bikochu?!
We were being watched all this time.
Ever since we arrived...
You were aware of that?!
You're the only one who didn't know.
Why didn't you tell me?!
Because if we told you
you'd have raised a big fuss!
And the insects would flee!
All the insects...!
Including the Bikochu!
If they tried to steal the Bikochu
from us through force
the insects would be in danger
of getting hurt.
So they captured Hinata and
decided to go with a hostage exchange.
That's very smart of them.
Something smells sweet...
It's the smell of honey.
Bee's honey...
Bees...?
Hinata's scent ends here...
In that case...
Those guys waited for a moment when
Hinata was alone
and attacked her using bees.
I've heard that in the Hidden Stone Village
in the Land of Earth
there's a clan of insect handlers
who primarily use bees.
The name of that clan is...
the Kamizuru Clan.
Kamizuru...? That's a name
that isn't heard very often.
Seems they were once hailed as being
at a level equal to the Aburame Clan...
But they aren't anymore?
This is a story from
the times of my grandfather...
There was a time when the Shinobi
of the Hidden Stone Village
were going to invade the Leaf Village...
The Kamizuru Clan was designated
to spearhead the operation...
The plan was to create
a disruption by releasing
a large swarm of bees into the village
followed by an invading main unit...
However, the Aburame Clan
wised up to that
and prepared to engage the enemy
in the forest to the west!
This battle between insect handlers
which had no precedent in history...
ended in the Aburame's victory...
With this battle as the turning point
the Aburame Clan rose to
unchallenged status
in the Village Hidden in the Leaves...
On the other hand the Kamizuru Clan
was subjected to cold treatment
even in their own village.
I've heard that only a few of them
remain now...
So those people came here
to capture Bikochu, huh?
What the heck are those guys
planning to do with the Bikochu?
If my insects come back
we might be able to learn something...
I see... I've been captured...
The Village Hidden in the Leaves is
in a difficult situation right now...
Because of that incident
at the recent Chunin exam?
The Hokage was assassinated
and I hear they lost many Shinobi too.
Times are about to change dramatically...
This is a chance for us
the Kamizuru Clan
to distinguish ourselves.
But to do that...
The founder's Book of Secrets, huh?
A broad range of Forbidden Jutsu
for Insect Handlers
are apparently inscribed therein
among other things...
If we possessed that at the time of
the battle with the Aburame Clan
we wouldn't have lost...
However, Clan members have continued
to search for it for many years
but couldn't find it.
Do you really think
we can find it after all this time?
That's why we need the Bikochu...
I brought the keepsakes
of the founder, my grandfather with me...
When the Bikochu emerges
it will pursue the scent it recognizes.
And we should be able
to locate the Book of Secrets
that Grandfather hid just
as he was dying.
This strand of his hair
will surely lead us to it.
If we get our hands on
the Book of Secrets
and if we engage in some big action...
I am certain that... the people of
the village will also acknowledge us.
Those people are also desperately
seeking recognition.
Naruto...
Did you find out anything?
How about Hinata's whereabouts?
No... The other insects were probably
also done in by those guys.
Damn! Then our only choice
is to do what they want?
When I went to all that
trouble of finding it...
So you want to desert Hinata?
H-How could anyone possibly do that?!
I won't desert her no matter
what might happen!
Anybody who deserts a comrade is trash!
Exactly.
But then we'd be able to locate Sasuke
if we have this guy here...
Well I guess we'll have to think of
some other method of finding Sasuke.
Yeah... Right now the first thing
we need to do is rescue Hinata.
But do you think Hinata
would be satisfied with that?
The person who originally
thought up this plan was Hinata.
Huh? But...
It's true that I told her about
the existence of Bikochu...
However...
The odds of finding
a Bikochu are extremely low...
We thought that she should aspire
to an important mission
with an assured outcome for the village
rather than a mission with such low odds.
But Hinata didn't give up.
She argued persistently that
if there was even a small possibility
one should take on the challenge.
Th-That Hinata did...?
She was extremely forceful and
Shino and I had no choice but to agree.
It's the first time Hinata
ever volunteered for a mission.
For that reason too
I want to make this a success.
Yeah.
But when we don't know
where Hinata is how are we...?
There is one place where Hinata
will definitely make an appearance.
I see! The place where...
...the exchange with
the Bikochu takes place!
We will definitely have
a chance at that time.
All right!
We will recover Hinata without fail...
and we will also protect
the Bikochu to the very end!
We brought the Bikochu!
Return Hinata!
Place the insect cage
on that rock over there!
Hinata!
Release Hinata!
I must verify it first!
What's... the meaning of this?!
Are you trying to make a mockery
of our Clan? Of insect handlers?!
A Goliath beetle...
You gotta be kidding!
Now Shino!
What?!
Parasitic Insects!
Heh! Recovery successful!
All right!
Damn!
Naruto!
All right resign yourselves!
Your time's up!
What's this?
This one doesn't smell like Hinata!
Huh?!
Just as I thought...
Beeswax...?
There they come!
Damn! You jerk! You jerk!
Damn! All these things are honey...?!
Sorry Naruto...
But these damn bees!
There's no end to them!
Do we need to slash them
if they're honey?!
You two don't move from there!
Huh?
This is the genuine thing!
And furthermore it contains deadly poison.
It appears that genuine ones
are mixed in...
But they're indistinguishable
from each other!
Back me up for a little!
Wall of Insects Jutsu!
A-Awesome...
Amazing power for a Genin...
As might be expected from
the Aburame Clan... I guess.
The Kamizuru Clan...
Huh...? So you were aware
of that fact.
Return Hinata!
Of course our intention was
to return her...
But only if you calmly hand over
the Bikochu.
However...
It looks like you have
no intention of doing that!
In that case
what do you plan on doing?
If you're an insect handler
you wouldn't bring a delicate insect
like the Bikochu
to a dangerous place
like a battleground...
We'll finish you off right here...
and take our time afterwards
to search for the Bikochu!
Wall of Insects Jutsu!
That one doesn't have
any other tricks, huh!
Shino! Paper Bombs!
Take this!
1000 Bee Stingers Jutsu!
Insect Clones...?
Up to your annoying tricks, huh...
Shino! What are we gonna do now?!
Don't you think we should
go back there for a moment?
Those guys
might find the Bikochu!
No... that location will definitely be safe.
More importantly the first thing
we need to do is search for Hinata!
There's no mistake.
Inside here.
Hinata! Where are you?!
Hey! Be careful!
There's no sign of those guys
but it might be a trap...
Is she there?!
Hinata...?
Hinata!
Are you all right, Hinata?
I'll rescue you in a moment!
Just a little more!
All right... I got it off!
Naruto...
Thank you!
H-Hinata...?!
H-Hinata... stop that!
What do you think you're doing
out of the blue like that?!
Who... are you?
What are you talking about, Shino?
That's Hinata.
If you're really Hinata
you'd get red in the face
and faint if you hugged Naruto.
— Huh?
— Oh!
I see... But Akamaru's nose wouldn't fail...
What? The smell of two people
is mingled?
You're not Hinata?
Naruto... It's me...
I'm Hinata believe me.
In that case...
show us what you tried to stick
on Naruto's back right now!
A Paper Bomb?
So you were intending
to blow up Naruto!
I thought that would work...
You are...
I see the one on the hill
was a clone, huh...
Wearing Hinata's clothes...
That's how she was able
to compromise the smell.
Where is the real Hinata?!
I wonder where she could be?
I see...
Suzumebachi lured
the Aburame Clan, huh?
Well, it appears that your comrades...
place more value on the Bikochu
than on you.
There's nobody else coming
to rescue you.
Jibachi, let's search for
the Bikochu that those guys hid!
There's not much time until sunrise!
Right!
Don't even try to escape.
If you make even the smallest movement
out of the ordinary
those bees will cut the string.
Up ahead is the entrance to
a labyrinthine underground water vein...
If you fall in you'll pass into
the other world in an instant.
We don't wish to kill
anyone unnecessarily.
If you want to live
I suggest you just stay quiet.
How mortifying... I ended up being
a burden to everyone after all.
You guys are just like summer insects
who fly right into the fire!
If you're lucky we'll meet again...
That place isn't just an ordinary cave.
Hey! Let go! Shino! Naruto!
There's nothing else to grab on to.
Be patient until I've checked
the surroundings!
No!
A huge number of bee larvae!
Bee larvae, huh...?
But what's with their unusual huge size?
If you tell me where you hid the Bikochu
I'll spare your life.
I refuse!
Searching for the Bikochu is
the mission that we were given!
Then die!
Paper Bombs!
Damn! Let's go, Akamaru!
Fang Over Fang!
That sound is...
I see... They're still continuing to fight
without giving up.
This is not the time to be crying...
There's no way that I can give up.
I suggested this whole thing!
Byakugan!
There are 13 bees...
attached to the string.
If I can take them all down at once...
I'll be saved.
But to take down bees that small...
Impossible! This guy...
I told you before...
I don't know... when to give up.
Naruto...
Yes... I won't give up either!
I need to concentrate and
control my Chakra...
Fang Over Fang!
How many of them are there...?!
Kiba!
I-I can't muster any strength...
Somehow my body is...
No way!
The larvae in this hive's favourite food
is Chakra!
What?!
As long as you're in there
they'll go through the wall
to suck up the Chakra...
What's the matter...?
So have you decided
to tell me the location?
Now!
Four...
Five, six... ten...
Eleven, twelve, thirteen...
Damn!
Summoning Jutsu!
Would you like to be the feed
for the larvae...
or would you like to get out of here
and become the prey of this girl here?
Choose whichever you like!
kusottare na nyuusu ga toori sugite
crappy news pass us by
kimi wa kotoba wo nakusu
and you become speechless
boku no koe ja marude chiisa sugite
my voice is way too soft
kimi wa henji mo shinai
so you don't answer
kimi ga naiteru hitori de naiteru
you're crying, crying alone
boku wa dou suru boku mo naiteru no sa
what can I do? I'm crying too
yoru ni hitoribocchi no ore no sakebi ni nosete
"let my lonely scream ring out through the night"
zawameku jidai wo ore no supiido de buttobashiteku yeah yeah yeah yeah
I'll thrash this confused era with my speed, yeah
sanzameku yoru mo ore no supiido de buttobashiteku yeah yeah yeah yeah
and I'll thrash this confused night with my speed, yeah
tsunzaku gitaa to ore no supiido de buttobashiteku yeah yeah yeah yeah
I'll thrash them with my piercing guitar and my speed, yeah
katamuku sekai mo warui yatsura mo kechirashiteku yeah yeah yeah yeah
I'll take this sinking world, all its evil bastards, and kick their butts, yeah
What should I do? My body won't move.
I proposed this mission myself
wanting to help Naruto and yet...
I don't want to end up as
a burden to everyone anymore
that's what I aimed for but...
No, calm down.
I need to concentrate my Chakra
and remember that training!
I have no choice but to do it now!
That is the best I can do right now!
Next time:
"Burn Byakugan! This Is My Way of the Ninja."